- [Narrator] Are you
subscribed to Psych2Go?
According to statistics,
only a small percentage of
you who watch our videos
are actually subscribed.
If you enjoy our content and
would like to support us,
do consider subscribing.
This helps YouTube's algorithm
in promoting more of our
mental health content.
Thanks for being here.
Hey Psych2Goers,
do you often wish you
could stop feeling regret?
Ever since the dawn time,
people have struggled to find
the secret to the meaning of life.
And while there isn't an answer yet,
our centuries of shared
experiences and introspection
have brought us a few steps closer
by better understanding
what makes life worth living
and overcoming the
things that hold us back.
With that said, here are 10
mistakes you should never make
if you want to avoid lifelong regret.
Number one, taking loved ones for granted.
In one of the longest
and most famous studies
done on the psychology of happiness,
according to the Harvard
study of adult development,
psychiatrist Robert Waldinger found that
happiness is most strongly
correlated, not with success,
status, wealth or achievement,
but with the quality of
close personal relationships.
That's why when you're lucky enough
to have people in your life
who truly love and care about you,
you shouldn't take them for granted
or wait until it's too late
to spend time with them.
Number two, not following your dreams.
When we're young, it's easy for us to have
lots of hopes and dreams in life
because we feel like the sky's the limit.
But as we grow older, it gets
harder to follow those dreams
because of our everyday responsibilities,
such as paying bills and
maybe raising a family.
But if you truly have
a calling or a passion
that gives your soul purpose,
giving up on it in favor of
following someone else's idea
of what you should do in your life
or choosing the path of least resistance
is one of the biggest
mistakes you can make.
Number three, not expanding your horizons.
As the famous movie quote goes,
life is short the world is wide,
and I wanna make some memories.
Whether it's traveling the world,
moving to a new city, taking a risk,
or simply trying to allow
yourself to discover
all the great experiences
life has to offer.
Because if you don't,
you'll spend the rest of
your life during, what if?
Number four, wasting your time
on things that don't matter.
The older you get, the more
you realize things like
gossip, fake friends,
popularity, social media,
pretending to be someone you're not
and always worrying about
whether other people like you
won't really matter in the end,
and yet we can't help it
waste our time on them anyway.
The sooner we realize there
are so many better ways
we could be spending our time and energy,
the better off we'll be.
Number five, settling into
relationships too quickly.
Even if you don't believe
in romance, destiny,
soulmates or true love,
that's no excuse for you
to simply settle for a
relationship you're not happy in
or fulfilled by just because you're tired
of waiting for the right one
or afraid you'll end up alone.
Both you and your partner deserve someone
who accepts you for who you really are,
who will love you in
spite of all your flaws
and make you happier than you
ever thought you could be.
So don't settle for anything less.
Number six, compromising your health.
Do you smoke or drink a lot,
or maybe you just don't
exercise regularly,
or you eat a lot of junk food?
It's easy to neglect your
health when you're young,
but don't make the mistake of waiting
until it's too late to start
taking care of your body.
No matter how busy your schedule,
you should find time to eat well,
exercise and get enough rest.
Avoid unhealthy habits like smoking,
overeating and binge drinking
and your older self will
be grateful to you for it.
Number seven, getting in debt.
You know the saying never bite
off more than you can chew?
That definitely applies to our attitude
towards money and spending.
Sure saving money can seem like
it's not a big priority right now,
especially when splurging on
impulse buys and luxury goods
like lavish vacations or expensive phones,
gives you such a high,
but you'll regret going into
more debt than you can repay
when the time comes.
Number eight, being overly
dependent on others.
Of course, it's only natural
for us to feel lonely from
time to time, and when we do,
we tend to gravitate towards other people
for comfort and reassurance.
But it's another thing
entirely when we do it so much
that it makes us dependent
on them for our happiness,
self-esteem and sense of identity.
Remember, people who are
emotionally dependent on others
often become clingy, needy, moody,
unsuccessful, and unhappy.
Number nine, having a bad
relationship with yourself.
One of the worst ways
you can destroy your own
chances at happiness and success
is by having a negative
relationship with yourself.
Yet so many of us are guilty of doing it.
We think that being self-critical
helps us become better
versions of ourselves
when really the opposite is true.
When we are kind empathetic, encouraging,
and supportive of ourselves,
we flourish so much more.
So know your worth,
let go of those limiting beliefs
and start practicing self-love
to start living a better life today.
And number 10, forgetting
to live in the moment.
Last, but certainly not least,
let's say never forget
that life is fleeting
and every moment is precious.
Sometimes we get carried away
by the hustle and bustle of everyday life
and we start to take
all the simple pleasures
and worthwhile moments
in life for granted.
We are so caught up in
our future and our past
that we fail to see all
the good we have have
right in front of us, right now,
here, in the present moment.
In the words of Anne Frank,
how wonderful it is that nobody
need wait a single moment
before beginning to improve the world.
And the same applies to your life too.
So do you agree with all the
things we've mentioned here?
Let us know in the comments below,
and if you sometimes find yourself
making some of these
mistakes, that's okay.
Remember that it's never
too late to change,
that's the beauty of life.
Also remember to like and share this video
with those who might benefit from it.
And as always, thanks for watching.
We'll see you next time.