(gentle guitar music)
(writing utensil scratching)
(bell dings)
- [Narrator] Hey, Psych2Goers,
and welcome back to another video.
Thank you so much for being here.
With your help and support,
we're able to succeed in our
mission to make mental health
and psychology more
accessible to everyone.
So, thanks again.
Now let's get into it.
Are you feeling a little lost in life?
Are things feeling stagnant and unmoving,
like you're not progressing
towards any of your life goals?
Do you feel like you're just
repeating the same routine
day after day with nothing to show for it?
Nowadays life is primarily centered
around working a good
ol' nine-to-five job,
or if you're still in school,
studies and assignments.
And this takes up so much of your time
so it's perfectly normal
to feel like you're stuck,
and that's okay.
The important part is to take action
whenever you feel like things
aren't going the right way
or when they're not going anywhere at all.
So here are five small
habits that have the power
to change your life around.
Number one, write down three things
that you're grateful for.
Has something ever happened
that was really important?
And you wanted to remember it
but then you didn't write it down,
then so you wound up
completely forgetting about it.
And you simply can't rely on your memory
to store every important
aspect and moment of your life.
Time passes and you might forget about
some of the important things
or the things to be grateful for.
Writing down things
you're grateful for will
help you foster gratitude
and allows you to think back
on what's happened in your life.
Helping to shift your perspective.
Studies show that fostering gratitude
will help you sleep better at night,
lower your stress levels,
and improve your
interpersonal relationships.
Taking up the habit of
writing down three things
you're grateful for in a gratitude journal
will create nothing but
positive change in your life.
Number two, clean for 10 minutes each day.
Have you ever felt
overwhelmed with the thought
of cleaning your apartment or your room
because of how much
time it's going to take?
Well, to avoid feeling overwhelmed,
it's best to break down your
tasks into smaller portions
in order to make it feel
more manageable and doable.
10 minutes is a reasonable amount of time
to devote to cleaning.
It inspires confidence that you can do it.
And it's also enough time for you
to get something small done.
Try folding and hanging your clothes first
and then moving on and coming
back to your room to sweep
or vacuum for 10 minutes.
If your apartment just feels
too big to clean all at once,
try and start with one room at a time,
like in the kitchen doing dishes
or in the living room to
straighten up the couch.
If you can get something
small done in 10 minutes,
you'll be that much closer
to getting everything done
in a timely fashion.
Number three, take care of your skin.
Does your confidence take a hit
whenever you're upset about
your dry skin in the winter
or have a bad breakout?
Believe it or not,
the way your skin looks can be
directly related to how
you're feeling and vice versa.
According to dermatologist
and clinical psychologist
Richard G. Fried,
inflamed skin, thinning hair,
and brittle nails can be
physical manifestations
of your mental state.
These unwanted physical changes
can have a negative impact
on how you feel.
This will further worsen
your skin, hair, and nails,
and create a vicious cycle.
This is one of the main reasons
why taking care of your
skin is so important
since it helps to foster
a strong emotional state
with high levels of confidence
and a strong and positive outlook on life.
Number four, implement
the 80/20 principle.
The 80/20 principle was
first observed in the 1800s
by an economist named Wilfredo Pareto.
He noted that 80% of the land
in his home country was owned
by 20% of the population.
This principle holds true
nearly 200 years later
and can even be applied
to different topics
such as business or athletics.
Are you wondering if this
principle can be applied
to your life and how?
Well, it's been found that
80% of your success will come
from just 20% of your work.
This means that 80% of what
you do will be unimportant
or irrelevant to your success.
The main point of applying
the 80/20 principle
into your life is that you
identify that 20% of the things
that you do actually result in success.
A simple way of identifying the 20% is
by making a to-do list with
your most important tasks
at the top, and the least
important at the bottom.
Finally, cross out 80% of
your tasks from the bottom
so that you're only left with the top 20%.
By doing this, you will
improve your productivity
and efficiency by focusing all
of your efforts on the tasks
that will actually yield success.
Number five, implement
effective daily routines.
Do you happen to wake up
in the morning feeling
tired and unmotivated?
This can be a telling sign
that your daily routines
are not working properly
or effectively for you.
Daily routines are broken
down into your morning routine
and your evening routine.
An effective morning routine
should stimulate your body
and mind while giving you a
boost of energy and inspiration.
Of course, everyone has a daily routine
that is unique to them,
so you'll need to find
what works best for you.
For the morning time, you
could read the morning news,
go out for an early jog,
or listen to a podcast
while you get ready for the day.
Now, let's talk about an
effective evening routine.
The main purpose of your
evening routine is to de-stress
your body and mind after a
long day of work or school,
while also gradually
preparing you for bed.
During this time, you should
do things that you enjoy
and engage in quiet hobbies
like reading, writing,
or watching a relaxing TV show.
If you're looking to change your life
by implementing these habits,
it's important to remember
that habits are difficult to build
and can take some time to
properly put into practice.
Focus on implementing them one by one
without rushing anything,
and you'll surely feel like
your daily life is slowly
turning in the right direction.
If you've found this video helpful,
like and share it with someone
who might benefit from it too.
And the studies and
references used are listed
in the description below.
Don't forget to hit the subscribe button
for more Psych2Go videos.
Thank you for watching and
we'll see you next time.