(spirited music)
(spirited upbeat music)
(spirited dramatic music)
- What's up, guys?
In this video, I will give you five tips
on how you can shoot a travel video
with your iPhone.
I'm currently here in Hurghada, Egypt,
here on vacation,
and I thought it would be a great idea
to give you guys some tips
on how to shoot a travel video,
but still be able to enjoy the moment
while traveling.
The best part about
filming with a smartphone
is that you don't have to
bring a lot of gear with you
to create great-looking videos.
In fact, the less gear you bring with you,
the more creative you will have to be
when it comes to shooting your videos.
For me, when I'm traveling,
I like to keep it mobile and lightweight.
When it comes to capturing moments,
I want to be able to do that
quickly and efficiently.
With that in mind, here are five tips
that will help you create
better travel videos.
Tip number one is to travel light.
Sometimes we think we have to bring a lot
of gear with us
to create the shots that we need.
Try to be creative
and only bring the
necessary gear with you.
Try to challenge yourself
using the tools you have with you.
If you don't have a drone,
use a tripod, for example,
or anything that can bring
your camera high above ground
to create that fake drone shot.
Also, when traveling light,
you are able to capture
moments much quicker,
and makes the trip more enjoyable.
Here are the tools I bring with me
whenever I travel.
Now, obviously the iPhone 13
Pro Max is always with me,
but what I additionally
bring is a smartphone gimbal
which is the DJI OM 4.
And what I like about it is
that it has a magnetic clamp
that allows me to go handheld
in a matter of seconds.
I also find it convenient
to use the DJI OM 4
as a power bank
since shooting videos can
drain the battery quickly.
And because you're on the go,
it is hard to find a place
to charge your phone.
Now, a lot of my shots are handheld,
but there's certainly also moments
where I prefer using a gimbal
to add more movement into my shots.
Now, the gimbal is also great
for capturing hyper-lapse
which I love to include
in my travel videos,
but also static shots
where I just place my
gimbal on a even surface
to create a time-lapse video.
Now, tip number two is to shoot handheld.
Like I've mentioned,
most shots made during my travel videos
are shot handheld.
The travel video of Istanbul, Turkey
was shot 80% handheld.
For me, shooting handheld
is the quickest way
to capture moments.
To get the best handheld results,
shooting in a high-frame rate,
such as 60 frames-per-second,
to then slow it down in post,
which helps smoothen out the shots.
Additionally, I like to add
image stabilization in post
to get the best results possible.
As you can see, you don't
necessarily need a gimbal
to create dynamic looking shots.
If you need to create static shots,
such as a time-lapse,
instead of bringing a large tripod,
use a gimbal or a GorillaPod,
which is much smaller in size,
portable, and versatile to use
as you can wrap it around objects
like a pole or tree.
Tip number three is body posture.
Whenever shooting handheld,
you want to keep your
arm close to your body
and create a two-point contact
as this will help smoothen out the shot.
You also want to walk heel to toe
to avoid up and down movements.
This way, you will make your shots
look much more natural.
When holding your phone,
try to hold it in a way
with one hand supporting
the bottom of the phone
and the other hand placed
towards the center of the phone.
You will notice that you'll
have much better grip
and can therefore control your
camera movements much better.
Depending on your shot,
this isn't always possible,
but whenever you can,
try to apply this method.
Also, while recording your videos,
try to hold your breath
as this will also help make
the shakes less apparent.
Tip number four is to make sure
you get a variety of shots.
Try to shoot as many angles,
focal lengths and movements
as you can think of
to make your videos more interesting.
Include wide-angle shots
to establish the scene,
but also capture detailed shots
that are important for the story.
I often see people doing the mistake
of just capturing wide shots,
which can quickly get boring.
Shoot the scene from different angles
so that you can cut between the shots
to make the video more engaging.
The best travel videos are those
with many creative shots in it
that make you feel like you're there.
Also, the more of a
variety of shots you have,
the easier it is for you
to piece the clips together in the edit.
Only around 10% of all the videos I shoot
when it comes to travel type videos,
end up in the edit
as I only take out the best portion
of the video.
As a rule of thumb,
shoot more than you need,
but also be purposeful with your shots
so that it fits with your edit.
This leads me to tip number five,
which is to shoot to edit.
The tendency most beginner filmmakers have
is to shoot everything they see
without giving much thought.
Before you start recording your video,
think about why you're shooting it
and how it fits the overall story
that you will be telling
when editing the video together.
A good idea is to do some pre-planning
to have a rough idea
of how you want the video to look like.
How do you want the people to feel
when they see your video?
And based on that vision
you have in your mind,
you can start shooting more purposefully.
What I like to do is to search
for the music beforehand
to get a good idea of how
the video should feel like.
Also when it comes to transitional shots,
having the edit in mind is very important.
Think about how you
should film the next shot
to match it with the previous shots.
This way, your videos
will have a better flow
and will make more sense in the edit.
So, a bonus tip I have for you guys
is to try to include a
subject in your video.
This will make your
videos more interesting
and you can really focus on a subject
that is doing something
and build a story out of it.
Now, there could be moments
where you're traveling alone,
so it's a good idea to
maybe ask the local people
if they would like to
be part of the video.
You will be surprised that a lot of people
would love to part of your video.
I, for example, love
to take portrait video
where the subject is standing still
looking directly into the camera
where I then create a slow-moving shot,
but it doesn't only have to be people.
What I like to do is also film birds
since they're also moving in a scene
and creates also a lot of interest.
Now, what's great about
filming the local people
is that they're always doing something,
and I usually like to capture
those moments as well.
So, don't be shy,
just go over to them,
and ask them if you could film them.
That's where you will create
a whole lot of a better story.
So, make sure to keep these tips in mind
the next time you create a travel video
as this will make your
life a whole lot easier.
Now, if you want to learn more,
make sure to check out
smartphonefilmmaking.com
which is my epic online course
with over 40 plus valuable content,
and is growing day by day
where you will learn everything there is
to filming high-quality videos
with your smartphone.
So make sure to not miss out.
The first 30 people to sign up
will receive a 30% discount
using the code SF30OFF.
So if you want to up your game,
make sure to take advantage of this offer
and start create your masterpiece
right there on your phone.
If you have any questions,
make sure to let me know.
Thank you for watching
and I will see you in the next lesson.
(upbeat music)