- [Narrator] Hey Psych2Goers,
welcome back to another video.
Are you subscribed to Psych2Go?
According to statistics,
only a small percentage of
you who watch our videos
are actually subscribed.
If you enjoy our content and
would like to support us,
do consider subscribing.
This helps YouTube's algorithm
in promoting more of our
mental health content.
Thanks for being here.
How're you doing?
Like, how are you really doing?
In these trying times,
everyone is struggling with
something behind the scenes,
whether it be mental health difficulties,
financial problems,
relationship struggles,
or school issues.
Life can feel so difficult sometimes.
In perspective, life is really short
considering we spend about 26 years
of our entire life sleeping.
So how do we make the most of life
knowing the uncertainties?
You have to ask yourself,
what does it mean to live a full life
and how can I achieve this?
Here are eight habits that can help you
live your best life.
Number one, take care of
all aspects of your health.
Do you eat a well-balanced diet?
While maintaining all
aspects of your health
may seem tedious, in the long run,
you'll be happier and healthier.
Put in a little time and effort every day
to take a walk, eat some
fruits and vegetables
or take some self-care time
to help prevent dealing
with health problems
later on in life.
After all, prevention is much cheaper,
less stressful, and overall healthier
than trying to treat any symptoms.
Knowing this, try to get into
the habit of treating yourself
with the same love and care
you treat those you love with.
Number two, self-reflect.
Have you tried journaling before?
If so, how was it?
And did you enjoy it?
Many people don't like to journal
because it seems too time-consuming
or they feel pressured
to have the prettiest,
most expensive supplies.
However, what's really important
is taking the time for self-reflection.
Whether it be by jotting
down your thoughts
on a scrap of paper or
recording a voice memo.
Taking even five minutes
a day for self-reflection
can help you immensely.
It allows you to figure out your values,
what you truly like and dislike,
and learn from past experiences.
So try to figure out
what reflecting methods
work best for you and
be authentic about it.
Number three, maintain social connections.
Do you make it a habit to
prioritize social connections?
While it's hard during a pandemic,
it's more important than ever.
Everyone needs a support system
no matter how independent
or introverted they may be.
Try to make it a habit to
maintain social connections
with friends and family,
even if it's simply a quick conversation
once every few weeks.
It'll help you lead a
balanced well-rounded life.
After all, your ups and
downs are meant to be shared
with people who love and care about you.
Number four, focus.
Have you ever tried to multitask?
While it's tempting to do so,
according to a study
by Stanford University,
multitasking is one of the
biggest myths out there.
In reality, your brain
cannot properly do two things at once.
Instead, it switches between them rapidly
giving the illusion of multitasking.
You'll end up taking
the same amount of time
or longer to do the tasks
with a significant decrease in quality.
This means you should
try to get in the habit
of focusing on one thing at a time.
If you're doing work,
shut off the television.
You'll likely end up doing
higher quality work faster.
Once the work is done,
you can fully enjoy your show afterward.
Number five, live in the moment.
When something exciting happens
is your first instinct
to take your phone out
and snap a picture?
Many people claim they do this
so they can look back on
and remember fond memories.
However, which is really going
to bring you more enjoyment,
a photo or fully experiencing moments
with your friends and family?
In the end, your thoughts and emotions
are likely going to give you
more enjoyment and fulfillment
than trying to take a
photo for social media.
With this in mind,
try to put your phone away
and truly enjoy the people
and experiences you get to be a part of.
Number six, manage your inner critic.
Do you have a little voice
in the back of your head
telling you that you're not good enough,
you're gonna fail or you're
not attractive enough?
There is a lot of pressure to be flawless
because we see perfection
from social media around us everywhere.
This can lead to low self-esteem
and a constant feeling
of not being enough.
While it can be hard to fix
the root cause of low self-esteem,
you should try to recognize
when you're being too hard on yourself.
If you can get into the
preemptive habit of realizing
when your inner critic is
getting the best of you,
you can break the thought pattern.
Try to remember that no one is perfect
and that's what makes people
so uniquely beautiful.
Number seven, complain less.
What's the worst day you've ever had?
At the end of it, did you let it all out
and have an hour-long rant session
with a friend or family member?
Complaining can be stress-relieving,
but if it gets out of hand,
it can end up doing more harm than good.
For example, by complaining
about something you can't change,
you're giving it more
power to ruin your day.
Also, you're more likely to be resentful
and hold grudges against people
you may not even see again.
This extra burden can weigh you down
without you even realizing it.
Instead, try to let go of
things you cannot change,
especially past experiences
you didn't learn anything from.
Remember that at the end of the day,
complaining too much
doesn't make you happier,
so why waste time on it.
And number eight, don't
be afraid to take action.
What's something that
you've always wanted to do?
Many people are afraid to try new things,
whether it be fear of failure,
thinking it's already too late,
or not being able to find the time.
However, there really is no better time
to take action than the present.
You can't assume you
won't be good at something
unless you try.
And even if you want the best,
the most important thing is to
have fun and enjoy yourself.
It's never too late to try something new.
So try to make time to do something
you've always wanted to do.
Do you think you'll try to
implement some of these habits?
Even though we can't fully
control what happens to us,
we can at least have
positive growth mindsets.
If you try your best to
maintain healthy habits,
chances are you'll end up
living the best life you can.
And in the end, that's all we can do.
So you don't have to
worry about being perfect
or trying to control everything.
Doing your best is enough
and you are enough.
Do you think these habits
will help you in life?
If so, how and which ones?
Feel free to comment down below
with your suggestions,
experiences or feedback.
If you enjoyed this video,
feel free to share it with friends
that might find insight
in this video as well.
Make sure to subscribe to Psych2Go
and hit the notification
bell for more content.
All the references used
are added in the description box below.
Thanks for watching and
we'll see you next time.