- All right, here's the situation.
It's February,
and Robin and I are gonna
be spending a weekend
in New York City.
We're gonna take the
train because it's quick,
it's easy, and it's relaxing.
And while we're up there
these are the things we're gonna be doing.
Cocktails and a nice
meal, just the two of us,
walking around maybe doing some shopping,
dinner with a couple friends
at really nice restaurant,
an early brunch,
and then finally, heading home.
So let's get packing.
(soft music)
I'm Brian Sacawa.
This is "He Spoke Style,"
advice and inspiration
to help you dress well,
develop your personal style,
and be more confident.
So in this video,
I'll be showing you what I'm gonna pack
for this very specific situation.
I'll go through the basics.
those essential things that I always have
to have with me when I travel.
I'll show you the
specific clothing, shoes,
and accessories that I'll be packing.
I'll do a rundown of
each individual outfit
I'll be bringing.
And finally,
I'll show you how I actually pack it all.
Now, although this is very specific
to my particular situation,
if you follow the
framework that I laid out
at the beginning of the video,
it'll be very easy for you to adapt it
to your specific needs when
you're planning your next trip.
The first thing to consider
is when you are going?
What season is it?
What's the weather gonna be like?
It's the first step in
planning what to pack.
Second, how long are you going for?
This will start to help
you focus in on the amount
that you'll need to pack,
how big of a bag you're gonna need,
and also some specifics
like how many pairs of
underwear you should bring.
Third, where are you going?
Different destinations
require different clothes.
So what I bring for a weekend in the city
is gonna be very different
than what I bring
for a weekend ski trip.
Fourth, how are you traveling?
Car, bus, train, plane?
That impacts not only the
type of luggage you'll bring,
but also the outfit you
wear when you travel.
And finally, and probably
most importantly,
what are you going to be doing
while you're on that trip?
Knowing your itinerary,
where you're going,
where you're eating,
the dress code or vibe
of each of those things
is essential to planning each
specific outfit for your trip.
And planning ahead is what
this all really boils down to.
Knowing when you're
going, where you're going,
how long you're going
for, how you're traveling,
and what you're gonna be doing,
makes it so much easier
to pack more effectively
and efficiently.
Alright, so now let's actually
talk about the basics.
And I'm gonna head over
to the desk to talk
through those things
beginning with my luggage.
So the bag I'm gonna take
is this rolling carry on.
It's very lightweight.
It's got plenty of room.
The two dividers here make it really easy
to secure everything inside.
It's very easy to stow,
and both the telescoping
handle and the wheels
make it really comfortable
and easy to maneuver.
For weekend trips by car,
I will typically use a duffle bag.
But since this trip is gonna
involve train stations,
taxis and subways,
the wheel carry-on makes a lot more sense.
Now, two of the biggest
challenges when packing any type
of bag are keeping things
organized and having enough space.
And one of the easiest
ways I found to solve both
of those problems is
by using packing cubes.
I absolutely love these things.
Everything is organized and contained.
Things aren't getting mixed
together or coming out the side
of the suitcase when
I'm trying to close it.
For a short trip like this,
I will use one of these in
place of my regular dopp kit
just to save some space,
but my favorite part about these
is that they are compressible which really
helps you maximize the
space in your suitcase.
Now when I travel, I like to read,
but the problem with bringing a book
is not only is it heavy,
but it takes up a lot of space.
That's why one of my
basic travel essentials
is a subscription to Audible,
today's video sponsor.
In addition to lightening my suitcase
and giving me more space,
what I love about Audible
is the incredible selection
of audiobooks.
Literally hundreds of thousands of titles
that they have across every genre.
Right now I'm in the middle
of "Spare" by Prince Harry,
which I highly recommend checking out.
It's very interesting and inspiring.
As an Audible member,
you're able to choose one title a month
to keep from the entire catalog
and that includes the latest
bestsellers and new releases.
Members also get full access
to a growing selection
of included audiobooks, Audible originals,
as well as thousands of podcasts.
And you can download and
stream all included titles
as much as you want.
Let Audible help you
discover new ways to laugh
be inspired, or be entertained.
New members can try it free for 30 days.
All you gotta do is visit
Audible.com/hespokestyle
or text hespokestyle, all one word,
to 500-500 to try
Audible free for 30 days.
Up next, couple small things.
First, gotta have some
headphones to listen
to those audiobooks, podcast, music.
And I always take a
Power bank or two with me
to keep my phone topped
up throughout the day.
Nothing worse than running out of battery.
Now, anytime you are stuffing
clothing in a suitcase
it's gonna get wrinkled.
There's no way around it.
And that's why I always
travel with a steamer.
I never rely on my hotel to have one.
And if you've ever tried to
use an iron as a steamer,
you know it doesn't really work that well.
So that's why I always
make room to pack my own.
Another clothing maintenance tool
that I always travel
with is a clothing brush.
Helps me keep everything
lint and pet hair free
as well as looking clean and new.
And finally, we have a watch roll.
You guys know me.
I like to have options for the wrist
and for the variety of
things we're gonna be doing
from casual to formal,
I'm definitely gonna need
more than just one watch.
Alright, so those are the basics.
Now I'm gonna quickly run
down my entire packing list
to include all the clothing, shoes,
and accessories I'll be bringing with me.
I'm only gonna bring one coat with me
so it needs to be warm,
it needs to be versatile,
so I'm going with a
classic camel overcoat.
Next, brown plaid sport coat
and gray chalk striped flannel
suit for my tailored items.
Because it's winter,
I'm going heavy on cashmere sweaters.
I've got a black turtleneck,
a cream turtleneck
and a Navy V-neck.
Two shirts, a light blue button
up and a denim button down.
Three pairs of pants, mid gray flannel,
blue jeans, and black jeans.
Since space is at a premium
I'm going with only two pairs of shoes,
formal and casual.
We've got brown oxfords
and white leather sneakers.
Onto accessories,
a tan knit hat, big brown scarf,
a brown silk pattern tie,
white silk pocket square,
two white T-shirts,
two pairs of underwear,
two pairs of gray socks,
one pair of blue socks.
And for watches,
we're going with watch
number one on a mesh strap,
watch number two on a brown leather strap,
and a watch number three.
So that kind of seems like a lot,
but it really is the minimum that I need
for the range of things
that we'll be doing.
And it also ensures that I'm not gonna be
wearing the same outfit more than once.
I'll show you how I'm gonna
pack everything in just a bit.
Trust me, it is going to fit.
But before I do that,
let me give you a rundown
of each individual outfit
that I'm going to be wearing.
So the first look here is the
outfit I'll be traveling in
from Baltimore up to New York.
We've got the camel
coat, black turtleneck,
paired with some medium
blue jeans, big brown scarf,
tan knit cap, white
sneakers, and the watch.
It's casual,
but a nice mix of sporty and
tailored with the overcoat
and the sneakers.
But the most important thing
is that it's comfortable,
which is exactly what you
want when you're traveling.
Look number two is for
our evening out together
after we get in,
you can see that I've
repurposed the black turtleneck
that I wore on the way up and paired it
with a brown Glen plaid flannel sport coat
and some mid gray flannel pants.
Anchoring this look are the brown Oxfords.
And on my wrist, we
have a beautiful watch.
Didn't wanna be too fancy,
but definitely wanted to
be elegant and refined,
so a turtleneck with a sport
coat is a great way to do that.
And of course camel
overcoat pairs effortlessly
with this look.
So for running around
the city the next day
doing a little shopping,
we're going with a slight variation
of the first travel look.
Once again, the camel coat,
which I'm pairing
with the cream colored
cashmere turtleneck,
black jeans, white
sneakers, big brown scarf,
tan knit hat, and the watch.
I feel like this look is very New York.
It's cool, it's a little edgy.
It also feels very simple
and effortless to me,
so really the perfect look for a morning
and possibly afternoon
running around the city.
I am a firm believer
that you really make your
own occasions to wear the
things that you want to wear.
And a fancy dinner with
friends in New York City
is the perfect opportunity to put
on my gray double breasted
chalk striped flannel suit.
I'm wearing it with a
light blue button up shirt
which I've paired with a brown
silk pattern tie to tie in,
seriously, no pun intended,
with the dark brown Oxford shoes.
Dash of elegance in the breast pocket
with the silk pocket square
and as well as on the wrist.
Throw on the camel overcoat,
and I am ready to head to the restaurant
for a tasty cocktail, delicious dinner,
and great company.
Look number five needs
to pull double duty,
because we're having a casual brunch
before we head to the train
station to travel back home.
So I'm going with a Navy V-neck layered
over a denim button down
and paired with some medium
blue jeans, white sneakers,
big brown scarf, and
the watch on the wrist.
Nothing fancy at all, just
casual and comfortable.
Great for an easy brunch and a two
and a half hour train ride back home.
Alright, so you've seen my essentials,
my entire packing list,
what each outfit looks like,
now it's time to pack it all up.
Alright, so first thing I'm gonna pack up
are my tailored items
beginning with my pants.
Now, the way I fold my
pants when I pack them
is to just fold them in half
once and then one more time,
so they're folded into quarters.
Next, the jackets.
Now the trick to folding a
sport coat or suit jacket
so it packs well is to basically turn one
of the shoulders inside out.
Then you nest the other
shoulder inside of that
make sure everything's lined up,
and then fold the jacket in half.
Now once again, the
shoulder goes inside out,
other shoulder nested inside that,
everything's lined up and folded in half.
These items go into the large packing cube
and I'm not gonna compress
it just to keep them
as wrinkle free as possible.
Shirts next.
Now the first thing I do is
to button up most of the front
of the shirt, turn it over,
fold one sleeve over and
then bring the cuff up
to the collar.
Same thing with the other sleeve.
Then I will fold the
shirt over into thirds
and into thirds one more time.
And that's how I fold the shirt.
So one more time here,
button up the front, flip it over,
fold each sleeve over,
and bring the cuff up to the
collar into thirds lengthwise,
and then into thirds one more time.
Next, I'm doing the sweaters.
Nothing fancy here,
just folding the sleeves under
and then folding the
sweater in half once more.
Then in this cube,
I'm also gonna put my jeans
and two white T-shirts.
All that goes into the cube, zip it up,
and compress to save some space.
Socks and underwear into the small cube,
zipped up, and compressed.
For my tie, I do have a travel
case that I like to use.
I'll fold the tie in half twice,
put it into the case,
buckle it in, and zip it up.
Toiletries next.
As I mentioned, using another cube,
instead of my regular dopp
kit to save space in my bag.
Now, the fun part of packing everything
into the carry-on.
On the left side,
that's where the large packing cube
with my tailored items goes,
I'm also going to put one shoe on the side
as well as the watch roll.
On the right side,
first the medium packing cube up there.
Then I'm going to lay the
tie case to the left of that.
Toiletries next,
followed by a second shoe.
Clothing brush goes here,
travel steamer goes here,
and the cube with the socks
and underwear goes here.
Cinch that down.
Throw the power bank in right here
and the pocket square over here.
Then all I gotta do is
close it up, zip it up,
and I am ready to go.
And voila, there you have it.
I'm packed up.
I'm ready to go.
I actually really need to get outta here
to make it to the train,
but before I do,
I've got two things for you real quick.
First, of course wanna thank Audible
for sponsoring this video.
Reminder to go to audible.com/hespokestyle
or text hespokestyle, all one word,
to 500-500 to try
Audible free for 30 days.
And second,
if you want some more
winter outfit inspiration,
got that playlist right
over there for you.
Click that,
there are eight videos
and whether you're looking
for suited looks, casual
looks, sweater looks,
or just some ways to
upgrade your winter style,
that playlist will have
everything you need.
I'm outta here.
(lively music)