How to discover business opportunities
When Walt Disney started Disneyland in 1955,
the idea came from taking his kids to a park
to have fun.
According to Disney, "It started with me taking
my two kids around to zoos and parks.
While they were on the merry-go-round riding
40 times or something, I'd be sitting there
trying to figure out what you could do that
would be more imaginative.
I got the idea for a three-dimensional thing
that people could come and visit.
I felt that there should be something built
where the parents and the children could have
fun together."
Earl Nightingale said that "Everything Begins
With An Idea."
Also, according to Victor Hugo, "There Is
One Thing Stronger Than All The Armies In
The World, And That Is An Idea Whose Time
Has Come."
You see, the first step to discovering any
business opportunity is coming up with an
idea that will be the basis or foundation
for your business to grow.
In the case of Disney, it started with the
idea of coming up with an idea that will be
beneficial to both kids and parents.
The question, however, is, how can one come
up with a relevant business idea and how to
develop the idea to create the perfect business
for one's self and one's brand?
In this video, I’ll share with you how to
discover business opportunities.
This, I believe will help you become a successful
person.
If you’re new here, consider subscribing
so that you won’t miss other interesting
videos like this.
You see, Andy Boynton, co-author of The Idea
Hunter said, "The world around you is filled
with ideas that can be useful."
So, the first step isn't to start racking
your brain to come up with the most genius
idea whatsoever but to take time to search
around you and recognize some of the ideas
that lie around, waiting to be picked up by
someone who can develop the idea.
You're probably wondering why it is important
to start by recognizing or creating ideas
necessary to meet a need, right?
Harvey S. Firestone said, “If you have ideas,
you have the main asset you need, and there
isn’t any limit to what you can do with
your business.
Ideas are any man’s greatest asset.”
You know what?
Let's talk about what a business opportunity
is and also, what makes a good business opportunity.
Thereafter, we can further discuss how to
discover one.
What is a business opportunity?
A business opportunity is an attractive proposition
that provides the possibility of a return
for the person taking the risk, which in this
case is you.
This opportunity usually requires the provision
of a product or a service that is valuable
to the buyer or the end-user.
What makes a good business opportunity?
1.
It must meet a need
A good idea isn't necessarily a good business
opportunity if it doesn't meet a particular
need.
For instance, you may invent a brilliant technical
product that might not make much sense to
a school teacher because it isn't in any way
meeting any needs of hers.
Remember what we said earlier about business
opportunities?
It must be valuable to the buyer or the end-user.
In the case where the need is already being
met, you can come up with ways to make it
even better.
For instance, the idea of a park wasn't new
but Disney simply came up with a way to make
it better, by involving parents in the fun.
2.
The opportunity should and must work in the
location that you are establishing it
Again, you need to consider the location of
the business.
For instance, what is considered to work in
one location might not work in another.
For instance, making and selling fur coats
in temperate regions might not be a good idea.
However, in tropical regions, you can be sure
to make sales as long as other business conditions
are considered and met.
If the opportunity meets a need that's great,
but it isn't going to mean much if that need
isn't specific to your location.
There has to be a demand for the business
to thrive.
3.
The right pricing for the market
When considering the need that your idea is
solving or required to solve, you should also
consider the people that the product or service
is intended for.
Hence, your pricing should be based on the
market.
For instance, if your product is targeted
towards helping the need for a low-income
earner, then the product/service shouldn't
be overpriced, but easily affordable for them.
Ask yourself whether or not you can provide
the product or service at a price the market
can handle.
Will your price attract customers while still
earning you a profit?
Now, that we know what a good business opportunity
should look like, how can we discover one?
1.
Recognize and listen to your potential target
audience
Remember what we said about every business
starting with a good idea?
Let's consider Disney's idea once again.
After the thought of making something that
can be favorable to both parties (parents
and kids), do you think he just replicated
the things he had seen in other parks into
his or he had to come up with interesting
things that can captivate the parents?
Of course, he had to.
In this situation, the parents were his target
audience, not the kids.
So coming up with fun things for the parents
means he had to listen to his target audience
by doing several types of research before
eventually building Disneyland.
Once he built Disneyland, he will spend days
and nights in there, observing guests, ride
operators, food servers, merchandise, and
custodial staff to find out what some of the
challenges were, what people were complaining
about and they could make these things better.
For instance, he was able to discover things
like low ride capacity, congested walkways,
traffic jams, and slow food service.
If your business is going to thrive, then
you need to learn to listen to your audience,
after all, your goal is to serve them, not
yourself.
2.
Take a clue from your competitors
You see, there are so many companies out there
that are probably doing what you are doing
or what you want to do, which is why you need
to identify what they are not doing but is
equally valuable to your target audience.
You can do a competitive analysis (don’t
let it lead to competitive paralysis though)
to see what other startups are doing, and
more importantly, not doing.
Doing this will help you recognize business
opportunities that can help expand your market
reach and develop your products and services.
3.
Understand the industry you are going into
Nothing speaks brand credibility and professionalism
than showing your expertise in your industry.
When you understand your industry, you know
what is important and what is not.
Mostly, you'll learn how to provide quality
products or services that will match the industry
standard.
Remember, in the end, you are not the only
person providing that particular product,
there are a good number of people as well.
Hence, the more recognized you are in your
industry, the better your opportunity of expanding
your market and sales, in return.
Summary
If you want to discover business opportunities,
1.
Make sure your ideas meet people's need
2.
Identify and listen to your potential clients
and customers so that you can continue to
serve them better, meeting their challenges
in creative and impressive ways.
3.
Do a competitive analysis and find out what
your competitors aren't doing so that you
can provide a much better solution for your
customers.
Good luck with your new or existing business.
Thank you so much for watching our videos.
Do you love to start your day with high energy?
Then, we invite you to join our new channel
which was designed to give you daily inspirational
videos that will help you to become a high
achiever.
We call it, “Inspiration Tube”.
Look at the description box to join the Inspiration
Tube
We Love You