hey guys welcome back to my channel
so 2020 has been quite different for us
as we have been doing a lot more road
tripping day tripping
um than we have typically we hop on a
plane and we fly somewhere however 2020
has put a halt to most of our trips
because we've had four trips cancel now
and so we have had a lot of time at home
and that means we have been exploring
our beautiful state here of minnesota
and we officially just booked a road
trip we are heading back to our favorite park in
the u.s glacier national park
if you've never been there you need to
go you just you just need to go
now we have not been to all the national
parks in the u.s so we can't compare him
to all the parks but for all the parks
we have been to
that one is hands down our favorite park
we've ever been to so
it has been six years since we have been
there and we are so excited to get back
there we literally booked the trip two weeks
before we leave and so
we've been busy getting ready for our
road trip and so with that said i just
wanted to share with you
our road trip snacks and meals because
things are a little different this year
with the pandemic going on and since we
are traveling from minnesota to montana
um there's different restrictions for
the states and so
montana unfortunately still doesn't have
quite all their restaurants and stuff
open so we've had to kind of figure
things out a little differently this
year hotels we're staying in they won't
have any breakfasts available
and a lot of the restaurants are like
takeout only so we've had to modify
however i think we have a pretty down
pat on what we will be doing and i just
wanted to share with you some ideas
in case you were road tripping in 2020
or into the future and most of these
items are all gonna be
more breakfast and lunch related not
really dinner related just because we
are planning to eat out dinner most
evenings unless there's nothing open
then we might be going to the grocery
store to just try and find like a salad
or something with another thing that
we've really thought of when we were
purchasing the foods for this road trip
where we did not want to have to cook
like we don't want to cook any more than
we have to so we are staying in hotels
so we don't have like kitchenettes or
anything so we just needed
easy healthy meals and that's what these
are so
no cooking really involved you might
have to use the microwave but that's
about it so
let's get started all right so first i
want to go over items that will be
in the cooler on ice and something
that's really important to us when we
are
road tripping we do try to eat healthy
as much as we can however
we are human we do like our sweets
that's just how it is so we will have
some snacks that probably aren't the
best for us
however we are always looking for items
that are you know a good source of
protein
and fats and carbs you know get a good
balanced meals
so i think we did pretty good so let's
get started on the items that will be in
the cooler so as i mentioned because
we're in the middle of pandemic the
hotels are having to change a lot of
things and with that said
there aren't really any continental
breakfasts and that will all depend on
the state that you're actually going to
um but for montana there is none of that
going on so we will have to figure out
our breakfast on our own and
instead of going out for breakfast
because we like to get up really early
and get to the parks early
a lot of times the restaurants that do
have breakfast they don't open till
seven and then we're not in the park
till
eight or nine and that just ain't gonna
work for us we're early birds so one
thing we decided we are gonna hard boil a bunch
of eggs and that is a great source of
protein for breakfast
and they're super easy to carry and
snack on so hard-boiled eggs are
definitely top of our list
also we have lots of yogurt so we both
have our own yogurts that we like my
husband likes
uh this kind and they are greek yogurts
we do prefer greek yogurt over others
they're great because they're
individually packaged
and they're easy to just bring on a road
trip another really easy breakfast item
are these pre-made breakfast burritos
and you just pop these in the microwave
now these are the egg cheese and black
bean so these are really great um there
are 230 calories and they have 10 grams of
protein in them these are really easy to carry in the
cooler and you just pop them in the
microwave and there's your breakfast
another really easy snack is cheese
sticks so we got a pack of cheese sticks
these are great sources of protein fats
and then my husband got some wisconsin
smoked string cheese he had to have that
so
okay so these are really good snacks to
easily carry next is carrots now i'm not
bringing this whole bag of carrots i
will be cutting these up and slicing
them into little carrot sticks however
we aren't quite ready to leave yet and i
don't want to do all that prep until
like right before we leave just so that
it's fresh and everything's ready
so they're not sitting so um carrot
sticks are awesome
it's a great little snack with like a
lunch and just a few other items that i
haven't picked up yet because like i
said i want everything to be as fresh as
possible right before we leave
is i will be getting some freshly sliced
deli meat that is how we always purchase
our lunch meat we get it fresh cut right
from the deli so
again i don't want to do that until like
the day before we leave and then i will
also get some lettuce for our sandwiches
as well as some cheese slices so
everything is fresh and ready to go
right before we leave for our trip i'm
sure you have seen a lot of our
sandwiches in my vlogs from our day
trips here in minnesota so yes that is
our plan for our road trip out to
glacier is having a lot of sandwiches for lunch
all right so now let's talk about dried
goods that don't have to be in a cooler
and they're easy to pack and easy to
bring with you hiking
first we have these rx bars now what i
love about these bars is that they have
tons and tons of different flavors
but they are literally the cleanest
ingredients you can get in a protein bar
literally all that's in these bars is
egg whites cashews almonds chocolate cocoa natural flavors
and sea salt that's it when you're looking
at other brands of
protein bars i mean they're packed with
so many different
things so these are literally the
cleanest protein bars i can find and
they are good so
these are great to just slip them in
your backpack if you're out hiking for
the day
so if you get hungry during your hikes
um you can just pull one out and snack
another snack that we love to have with
us and it's super easy to slip in your
backpack is
beef jerky so again this is a great
snack for when you're out hiking
if you get hungry just have some beef
jerky it's full of protein
and you're good to go we're bringing
some bread with us because as i
mentioned we do eat up sandwiches typically for
lunches when we are out road tripping or
day tripping
and if we get tired of sandwiches with
the meat the cheese
and the lettuce and we are gonna mix
things up and have
peanut butter and jelly so this is
actually great too for like breakfast if
you had a toaster in your room you could
make a piece of toast or something
otherwise peanut butter and jelly i mean
can't go wrong with that right another
really great find that
is the same brand as the rx bars is that
they have
rx oatmeal which i am so excited to find
this i haven't had any yet but i've
heard really good things about it these
little cups you just add water to them
and microwave them and the only
ingredients
in this little cup of oatmeal is oats
almonds dates egg whites apples natural
flavors and cinnamon so they do have a maple kind
and they have the apple cinnamon and they might have
had another flavor but i don't remember
they might have like a blueberry i can't
i might be wrong since these are really
easy to pop in our microwave
they're healthy and nutritious and we
can pair these with hard-boiled eggs if
we want or one of those breakfast burritos that
i just showed you and to go with those
breakfast burritos we had to bring some
cholula with because
all burritos must have cholula so we got
that little bottle and then some more
snappy items that we picked up
was a bag of this mountain trail mix it
has
peanuts raisins m m's chocolate almonds
and cashews so yes i did buy the kind
that had all the chocolate in it because
that's my favorite you can totally go
without those but i figured you know
what
it's okay we have a lot of hiking to do
i will work off all those m
ms i'm not worried about it we also
bought some sun chips just for like our
sandwiches again
a lot of our day trip videos you'll see
we're having sandwiches with chips so we
just bought some of these
for lunches and if you just saw in our
last vlog where we went to hike devil's
kettle and had lunch in grand portage
we had a war between chips ahoy and oreo
and so guess who won who won that little
debate which is better
that's right oreos it's a great way to
cure that little sweet tooth that i get
after meals and just a little bit of a healthier
snack are some apples so we're gonna
bring a little bag of apples too and
then we may
also pick up some bananas on the way out
there again i want them to be fresh
so i haven't picked any of those up yet
so this way we're still getting our
fruit in all right now let's talk about
drinks so staying hydrated when you're
out and about road tripping
and hiking and stuff for long periods of
time it is so important
so of course we are going to have lots
and lots of water with us
especially when we're in the park when
it's not as easy to go get water we have
to make sure we come prepared so we have a large
water jug that will be filled with water
and we also bring smaller ones for
in our backpack so we will have every
single water jug that we have with us
are going to be filled with water so we
stay hydrated during our time in the
park because we are going during a
pandemic a lot of the
nature stores and the restaurants and
all the things that are typically open
are not open so getting some of these
items is going to be harder so
that's why preparing for this trip has
been really important to us
it's not like we can just go pick some
up or something um
so we have to be prepared for this and
probably the second must
is my coffee nothing ruins a day more
than a bad cup of coffee
so yes our hotel in our room will have a
coffee maker however
how often do they really clean those i i
don't know it's always kind of gross me
out to use a coffee maker that is in a
room
that you know many people have used and
you don't really know how often they've
been cleaned so guess what we did for
this road trip
we went and bought ourselves this mini
five cup
coffee maker so we can bring it with us
and it is our coffee maker and we know
it's cleaned and good
and this is gonna be our little coffee
pot when we go so we can make
our coffee that we like i try to talk my
husband into bringing the espresso
machine but
he wasn't having that so that little
five cup coffee maker will do so we can
make our coffee this is what we drink
all the time we are caribou
fans and this is our coffee and then i
brought all my
little flavoring ingredients because i
love my mochas
this is not espresso so i can't make
them to the tea
of how i usually make them however i i
can handle it
i can do this i'm not worried about it
it's still gonna be good i got my
caribou coffee i got my sweeteners
my mocha stuff i'm good to go typically
with lunches we usually like to kind of
switch things up we do drink a lot of
water at lunch however i do
like to have a cola zivia typically for
lunch and so we are bringing a little
pack of these
and i don't know if these are going to
be items i can pick up
out there because they're not that easy
to get and then
same with my cop we are very picky
people with our coffee and
i don't know if we'll be able to get
this caribou coffee out in montana so
that's why we're bringing it with us
hubby is bringing a little case of beers
too for dinners lunches sitting down by
a lake or just
hanging out at our hotel or whatever he
just likes to have
a beer once in a while so he is bringing
this pack of indeed brewing company
which is from minneapolis
however when we do travel he loves
trying new beers from other states
but again i don't know how much of that
we're going to be doing because our plan
is to eat most of our dinners
out however it might be like takeout so
i don't know what the plan is with beer
so he's like well i'm just going to
stock up bring him with us we're road
tripping so and with that said i'm doing the same
thing i'm getting my wine bringing my
wine with me just in case
so one thing that this year has taught
us is that
at the end of the day if we went out for
dinner and go have drinks and stuff
that's really fun to do that but you
know what we have realized this year we
have loved bringing our own beers
our own wines and then just going to
like a park or to a beach or something and just
sitting down there and drinking our own
drinks because it's just more relaxing
than sitting in a bar and we just sit down on a beach and
watch the water or sit in a park or something we have
really really come to like that
so that's why i now pack these
mini wines and these are perfect for
just throwing into a cooler
and then bringing an insulated wine
glass
and then you can just fill up your wine
glass with these minis instead of
bringing a huge bottle but bring the big bottles so you can
fill the mini so we'll see how that
works
and to be honest it's probably saved us
a lot of money instead of going to buy a
nine dollar glass of wine
i think going to buy a ten dollar bottle
of wine and that was gonna last me a lot
longer
so one thing we have realized this year
it has been so fun to just go
down to parks with a pack lunch or
drinks and just sit there together and
not be in restaurants or bars to do that
trust us we still enjoy going out to eat
but it's been really fun to
have like the picnic thing this year
more than we have ever done so
i don't know i have a feeling we
actually might continue doing that
so if anything a little good did come
from this pandemic so i hope you found
this video interesting i hope it maybe
sparked some ideas for you or maybe
there was items you've never heard of or
seen i hope that this helps maybe gives you
some ideas and i hope if you are road
tripping this summer you are having a
great road trip have so much fun make so many
memories and enjoy your time now i want to hear
from you guys so what are some of your
favorite snacks that you like to bring
with you on road trips? so thank you guys
so much for watching if you haven't
already be sure to give this video a
thumbs up and subscribe for future vlogs
and be sure to go check out some of my
blogs from glacier national park because
we are so excited to get back out there
like i said it's our favorite so of
course i'm gonna be vlogging it because
it's so beautiful out there so we will
see you guys in the next vlog
bye guys