i feel like
crap but I made it I just took my
hair out of braids it's all wavy
oh that was like 20 plus hours of travel
foreign gonna use this tea tree
essential mask to start my day
hey it's Jackie and I'm currently in Seoul
back in 2019 I uploaded my first experience
in South Korea and I'm headed to the olive
young Awards and Festa think of it like a
big convention there's also Awards so these are
products that are really popular for Koreans and
they have amazing taste because I've already
used a bunch of products they're incredible
foreign
bow in my hair this isn't the dress I'm
wearing I'm gonna wear something a little
more conservative because in my first video
I wore a lot of strapless just because I'm
used to that and people were like yeah
and in South Korea like they tend to
wear higher necklines it's a little
more modest so I picked out an outfit
that I think is still my style but maybe a
little bit more appropriate Let's Get It On
we are headed out
I'm so excited to be in Seoul again it's snowing
let's head inside and check out some amazing
award-winning products that was better right
let's go check out the makeup
thank you
I think I got enough Clips there was a bunch
of games and I kept losing but they did give
me a lot of full-size samples to try out look
at this one this is for hair what else we got
so I hope you guys liked oh this is the sunscreen
this is one of their best sellers on Olive young
back from the convention I'm in the hotel with the
good lighting and I just changed to these J crew
pants pants I'm a little exhausted it's supposed
it's like 2 A.M in the morning I think for me but
me and Tyler are pulling through he did all the
shots of like behind the scenes and everything
so he's tired he loves a beer actually quite
cold so we're all bundled okay this is dinner
good morning breakfast time
I ordered from Olive young beforehand and
I've been loving using these products they
have quite a range so some things are more
affordable this is from their premium line
for example and I keep grabbing for this
really unique lip product here look at this
I'll show you the K Beauty look that I really want
to recreate this is sunny she's a beautiful Korean
influencer and I just love this makeup look so
I'm gonna be on the hunt for very similar shades
foreign
spot pad calming touch and they don't use
a lot of heart leaf in like North America
so this is kind of a unique product and it is
very calming I also want to try some toner pads
foreign
you're right
snow fox haul because we're hungry oh my gosh
day three in Korea it's another snowy day and
yesterday jet lag hit me and Tyler when we got
back to the hotel at around 4 30 we both passed
out and woke up this morning so I think we're
feeling good now and the first thing that we're
doing is going to get a Korean corn dog both never
had one before and yesterday I kept getting all
these notifications to my phones like emergency
alerts but they were in Korean so I could not
understand them but apparently there was a
hazardous dust warning within the snow there was
sandstorms coming in from China and Mongolia but
we're good now so we're gonna go head out
and enjoy the day I picked up this palette
yesterday I love the neutral tones where's my lip
product and I'm so obsessed with the packaging
final step I'm using the perfect serum mist
thank you foreign
we're here at the flagship line friends
thank you
time for a photo shoot yeah this is
before and after picket ears blue
a few moments later okay we couldn't
get it to work somebody just translated
it in English we almost killed each other yeah
I want all the flowers okay
I don't think you'll see it's so hard so
hard adorable should I go oh it's my hat
that's it that's cute okay and then which one
print it got canceled it was like an English yeah
part two foreign
we just went to some Flagship
stores I really wanted Tyler to
see these adorable characters and
then we headed to the knotted Cafe
thank you
foreign
I just finished filming for my main Channel and
I went over my favorite products that I've been
using all week that were all Olive Young Award
winners but I also wanted to share some behind the
scenes that I didn't really get on camera because
me and Tyler were just like very frustrated we
went shopping at the Lotte Tower which I've been
before so I was like comfortable going there and
we got a cab no problem and then we were trying
to get back and all the cabs were refusing us
like just saying no and I didn't know if we were
doing something like offensive if we were doing
something wrong turns out we weren't I Googled it
after and apparently it's a bit of a problem here
where um cab drivers will refuse you if it's not
like a long enough trip but we ended up doing the
public transit system which is incredible but
it's hard to navigate obviously when you don't
know what any of the signs say so Tyler came in
clutch he you know read the map he got us home it
really we really weren't all that far but um I was
close to tears and here's a video of me walking
after walking for way too long
and being a little over tired
Circle bus for her in this moment
I'm Claire I'm not a massive eclair
it's such a sunny day today I got these
yesterday and I think they're my favorite
thing that I got they sit on your
coffee cup I did get the sandwich
maker I do make a lot of sandwiches and
this is way more fun to make cramps better
they have so many favorites
picked up some nails from Olive
young I haven't tried them so I'm
hoping that they fit my fingers
well but I really love this one
I've got this beautiful cardigan from the mall
currently navigating on my own I'm gonna go
to try to find a Korean corn dog wish me luck
the corn dog was not meant to be I'm currently
at the coffee bean I have a really pretty drink
here but um yeah I walked all the way to a place
called dog and dog and it was a corn dog place
the like themed cafes so the quest continues but
I'm freezing it is so cold
so I got a really cute latte
intended with the lashes and the liner I ended
up re-filming this tutorial for my main Channel
because the light was just changing too much
in the room so my second attempt is now live
if you want to check it out and the outfit
is from the store that was the equivalent
of a Korean origia down to not having a beer in
the changing room but having to walk out to the
communal mirror and face judgment and I would have
loved to have sightseed more but we didn't end up
having enough time because it was quite a short
trip and I had to film and do a lot of content
if you want to keep watching and see Seoul in
the summer check out my previous video from 2019.
we did have one hour before heading to the airport
and went to the dollar store which was so much fun
about 60 for all this
we're off to the airport