welcome to indonesia
so here's our food which we ordered
at four o'clock in the night
tahu (tofu) with some chili what else do we
have tahu tempeh i don't know i think
this is tempeh only but it looks very nice
looks very nice and it smells very nice
and we are really really hungry we had such a
long trip really and you can see babe is hungry
we are the tempeh family and out of the
rice this is the rice oh yes this is
i didn't know about the portions
but i think we can we can get this
because we are both very hungry it
looks good so we're gonna eat now
so this was our first apartment the
best western in makassar we had really
nice views so you can see for example
here outside there is the mosque and
we have on both sides the views was really a nice
stay a good bed and yes lisa and so we are now
heading to our next stop and that's manoli i think
right manoli so what is also funny about this is
you can see all the residues let's
say i don't know if it's visible on the camera
from all the people looking at the
views here but okay it's very good
my god
so we have this amazing guy who is
giving us actually a real life concert
to the neighborhood to the neighborhood
what do you think about that it's amazing
it's nice to have this kind of like concert
he's so passionate passionate about
singing but we really like it and enjoy
wow
so this is a very nice waterfall in the
malino region yeah and you can see its beauty
so we have a really really
nice rainbow on this waterfall
very very nice
so we are now here at this really nice free
hanging bridge and it does not only look
shaky it is shaky and how shaky we
will see now so let us experience
you can see the maintenance of this
bridge is also not anymore the best and
there is a sign mentioning that we should
walk slowly over the bridge and so we will do
and already now i can feel the shaking
pretty crazy as you can see if you're
scared about this kind of thing i think
this bridge is not the way to go for you and
also you can see there are some kind of gifts
so till now everything is quite okay
even though we are standing still
the bridge is still a little bit shaking
and there's a small river
so hello here you have marquisa we bought it on
the market it's really a nice fruit i think it's
like a passion fruit or actually it is a passion
fruit you just simply can open it up like this
and you can eat it it's very tasty
really good we are in malino and
now we drive to bira bira beach
and there is a really nice beach nice surrounding
nice cliffs so we will enjoy the ride actually
takes roughly four hours on the motorbike but
we will manage and i hope it will not rain
see you later
and we're waiting for our delicious food very cool
look what we just found out here
a very very beautiful rice field just below
us here we directly need to make a stop
we just arrived here during our
motorbike tour to bira beach from malino
we just discovered this amazing rice fields here
just have a look on this view it's unbelievable
green the sun it's amazing look at all the
rice fields and also there and there amazing