Hi there.
Today let's talk about language learning.
Most of us have the idea that
language learning is difficult,
so I'm gonna share with you today
some research which is really
encouraging about language learning.
You know, our goal, our point,
our purpose is to help you
arrive at fluency in English.
And if you've done our Seven Rules
Course, you'll understand the mechanisms,
the method behind what we do here.
But language learning is a challenge.
So let me share this
encouraging research with you.
You'll be amazed, I think.
Oh, and what did I hear you say?
You haven't done the Seven
Rules of Adept English yet?
Well, you are missing out.
If you go to our website, you
can sign up for this course
straight away and it is free.
What have you got to lose?
The Seven Rules of Adept English
explains exactly how best to use our
podcasts so that you can arrive at
speaking English fluently more quickly.
Let's get on meanwhile, with that
encouraging research, shall we?
So an article published in The
Conversation back in August this
year, that's 2022, by Monika
Schmid of the University of York.
She's done some surprisingly encouraging
research about learning a language.
The article was published just after
the GCSE and A level results were
out, as usual in the UK in August.
So these exams are the ones that
16 year olds and 18 year olds take.
16 year olds take GCSEs, which
stands for General Certificate
in Secondary Education.
And the 18 year olds take their
A Levels or Advanced Levels.
And the A level results are what
determine whether or not they're
getting to university or onto some
other course of study or training.
So they're important exams.
You can take the IGCSE, the International
GCSE in many parts of the world and some
countries have GCSEs, just like in the UK.
They have GCSEs in Nigeria, for example.
And a lot of Commonwealth
countries do the A level as well.
So the evidence cited in this
newspaper article is very surprising.
They're saying that the knowledge
of a foreign language as learned
in school stays 'astonishingly
stable' over a long period of time.
Vocabulary here - 'astonishingly'?
Well, that's A S T O N I S H
I N G L Y, 'astonishingly'.
And that's an adverb,
it describes the verb.
And it's from the verb 'to astonish'.
If you 'astonish' someone, it means
that you surprise them, but it's
a lot more surprise - it's like
'extreme surprise', astonishment.
So 'astonishingly' means 'very, very
surprisingly' - stable, S T A B L E.
Now, that can be a noun and it's
where you might put a horse.
A horse's house is called 'a
stable', but here it's an adjective.
And if something is 'stable',
it means it's 'unchanging'.
So basically what we're saying here is
that if you learn a foreign language in
school, that foreign language knowledge
that you've gained is 'stable over time'.
It means you really don't lose
it, and that apparently is
so, even if you don't use it.
There is a phrase 'use it or lose it'.
And the suggestion here is for that,
for language learning that's not true.
So Professor Monika Schmid, the author
and the person who's conducted the
research, she cites another piece of
research that was done 40 years ago.
She says, The psychologist Harry P Bahrick
carried out an investigation of some
600 Americans who had learned Spanish in
high school up to 50 years previously.
Apparently, there's a small
amount of loss three to six years
after the lessons have ended.
But this researcher found mainly that the
knowledge of Spanish appeared 'stable'
even 50 years after they'd learnt it!
So it's as though, once it's learnt, these
words just stick around in your memory.
You don't forget them.
Rather like the words of your
native language, perhaps?
Even if you're not using them as
well, which I found surprising.
It's estimated that language learners
keep hold of 70% of the language learning
they've done, even if not using it.
But in other subjects,
that information erodes.
I'm thinking of History.
I can remember what I studied in
History at school, but I certainly
can't remember the detail of it.
In her study, Professor Monika Schmid
carried out tests on English speaking
people who were students of French 50
years ago, and they still remembered
the grammar and vocabulary just as well
as those who learned it more recently.
And that's true where they hadn't
used their French for many years.
I found that really
surprising and encouraging.
But once it's in your brain,
it's there for life it seems!
Professor Monika Schmid, I think it's
Schmid, S C H M I D, says "Some parts
of language, mainly the vocabulary are
memorized in the same way as facts, rules
of algebra, dates, names, and so on.
This memory system is indeed
vulnerable to (some) erosion."
That means you do lose a little of it.
She says.
" Other parts though, like grammar,
are learned in a way that is much
more similar to riding a bicycle.
We use the part of our brain that is
good at remembering rules and sequences.
So grammar becomes more like
a reflex and that kind of
knowledge resists forgetting."
That's the learning that we're
talking about that becomes automatic.
So is Monica Schmid saying that vocabulary
memory erodes, meaning it is lost?
Or does she not mean that?
That's a little bit confusing.
However, she does go on to say that
because vocabulary in another language
has its equivalent in your language,
it gets 'refreshed' each time you
use the word in your own language.
And that's even if you aren't using
your second language, and even if
they're not similar sounding words.
So she gives the example of
'banana' and 'banane' in French.
So every time you say 'banana'
in English, you are reminded
of 'une banane' in French.
She says that the neurons that contain the
words for an object also contain the word
in the other language that you learned.
So the word in your second language is
stimulated and refreshed every time you
use that word in your native language.
She gives the example of 'apple' in
English and the French for 'apple',
if you know it, is 'pomme', P O M M E.
If you're an English speaker, apparently
each time you say the word 'apple', the
French for 'apple' - 'pomme' is also
stimulated and refreshed in your brain.
So similarly, 'potato' will
stimulate 'pomme de terre' or
'Kartoffel', if you know German.
That's without you realizing it.
That's automatic and unconscious.
Professor Monika Schmid also makes the
point that it doesn't mean that you
can just start chatting in a foreign
language, fluently and automatically.
I think most of us language
learners do know that!
And it's perhaps the case that if you
learnt a language in school, you probably
didn't arrive at being fluent anyway.
It takes far more listening
to a language than is done in
school to help that happen.
But what it does mean is that grammar
and vocabulary that you learned up to 50
years ago is still in there somewhere.
You haven't forgotten it.
You haven't lost it all together.
We have a saying in English - 'It's
at the back of my mind',  meaning that
some piece of information or some memory
is not at the forefront of my mind.
It's not what I'm focused on,
but it's in there somewhere.
It can be 'wakened up', if you like.
Some of the people in this research
who were tested, learned their second
language 50 years ago in school.
They haven't used that language since.
And they still haven't lost it.
They could still answer the questions
and do quite well on a written test.
The human brain is amazing, isn't it?
The article also talks about how
there is a decline in the numbers
of students - children studying
languages at GCSE and A level.
That's disappointing.
In fact, amongst my three children,
when my daughters, who're older went
through school, it was obligatory
to learn a language at GCSE level.
They had no choice.
So I encouraged both of them to
learn French as we have family
in France and it makes sense.
However, now that my son is
doing his GCSEs, the language
learning isn't obligatory.
They're no longer made to do a language.
He knew I wanted him to do French,
but he didn't want to do it and has
chosen some other subject instead.
That seems a shame, especially when we
now know that your language learning
in school stays with you a lot longer.
A lot longer than any of us had realized!
So perhaps this research supports
the idea that language learning in
schools should go on for longer.
Most children in British schools
learn either French or German
and Spanish, probably up until
Year 9, so up to the age of 15.
And then they're permitted to drop it
when they choose their GCSE subjects.
I think rather like PE, a language
should be something that you continue
with for another couple of years because
this language learning it appears,
stays with you possibly forever.
So it's well worth doing!
But also let that serve as
some encouragement to you
in your language learning.
We do often think about how
difficult it is to learn a
language and how long it takes.
But I think this is encouraging.
Whatever vocabulary you commit - and
I would imagine it's - to long
term memory now, your brain will
remember it for many years to come.
Maybe even you'll remember
it in 50 years time.
Wow!
Your brain is amazing!
And getting the grammar to be automatic
and the vocabulary to be stored
in long term memory and available
and ready when you want to speak?
Well, of course, as we know, that's best
achieved by lots and lots of listening.
That's what we do.
That's what we help you
with at Adept English.
Enough for now.
Have a lovely day.
Speak to you again soon.
Goodbye.